JAI SINGH SRA

Phone: (852) 90151625 LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/jssra/</u>

Email: jais334@gmail.com Github:github.com/JaiGatsby

SUMMARY

Highly driven software engineer in finance with 2+ years of work experience with Python and Java at leading investment banks. Looking for a challenging quantitative role with a large degree of ownership and an accelerated learning rate.

EDUCATION

May 2015 - Jun 2019 B.Eng in Computer Science The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

GPA 3.

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017 Exchange Program University of Pennsylvania

EXPERIENCE

GOLDMAN SACHS

Jun 2019 - Present

Analyst [Marquee Strats]

- Worked on a Vertx based RESTful data service deployed on AWS using ElasticSearch and an in-house timeseries database
- Improved client satisfaction by implementing data quality checking and alerting infrastructure
- Improved adoption of API amongst non-technical users by exposing Python client via Excel
- Set up infrastructure to migrate TBs of data between instances of a KDB-like database
- Managed and mentored Summer Analyst in team

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

Summer Analyst [SecDB Architecture]

- Benchmarked cross-WAN streaming performance of various message queues and databases for binary objects
- Configured and worked with Datomic, Apache Cassandra, Tibco Rendezvous and Apache Ignite

SOCIETE GENERALE

Feb 2018 - May 2018

Software Engineer Intern [Equity Delta One]

- Migrated existing codebase onto Docker and created CI pipeline with Jenkins and Docker Swarm
- Increased system resiliency by using Hystrix to gracefully handle errors from downstream microservices
- Worked on production grade CQRS application running on Java Springboot

SET SAIL SOFTWARE

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

Natural Language Processing Intern

- Built chatbot to answer FAQs as an ensemble classifier
- Built and deployed an API interface for the ML models to EC2
- Developed technical NLP skills in NLTK, SK Learn, Jieba and Flask libraries for Python

PROJECTS

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Computational Electrophysiology *UPENN*

- Conducted statistical analysis on over 1TB of EEG data of subjects undergoing memory experiments to predict whether a piece of information will be successfully recalled later
- Analysis included computing ERPs, Fourier and Wavelet transformations, and regression models in Python

Feb 2017 - May 2017

Natural Language Processing HKUST

• Used unsupervised topic models like LDA to extract categories from raw text in Mandarin

VOLUNTEER

Feb 2020 - Feb 2021

Co-Captain New Analyst and Intern Committee GOLDMAN SACHS

- Organized social and professional events for incoming summer analysts
- Coordinated tasks across committee members and efforts in other regions